ctia.org 2016-10-29

# Privacy Policy

_  
Effective: November 7, 2013_

* * *

## I. Introduction

CTIA is committed to protecting the privacy of CTIA.ORG® users’ personal information.  In general, we collect and use information about you to optimize your experience on CTIA.ORG ®.  This privacy statement applies to the information that CTIA collects, uses, and shares from its CTIA.ORG® Website.  Please note that some of CTIA’s subsidiaries and various departments have their own websites dedicated to specific events and advocacy initiatives, and those websites may be governed by separate privacy policies. 

**Definitions**  
Privacy statements may often be confusing because they contain technical terminology.  In order to assist in your understanding of our policy, please consider reviewing some of the following terms:

> Cookies: Small text files created by a web server that are delivered through a web browser and stored on your computer or device and are used to identify your computer or device and record your preferences and other data so that the website can personalize your visit(s).  There are different types of cookies.  For example, many websites use their own cookies or “first-party cookies” to make their websites run more smoothly by doing things like keeping track of items in your shopping cart. Some websites also provide space for “third-party cookies,” which are placed on your browser by companies different from the company that runs the website you are visiting and may be used to remember parts of your online activities in order to deliver personalized ads or analyze web traffic.   
> 
> Encryption: The process of encoding messages or information in such a way that unauthorized parties cannot read it.  
> 
> Non-Personally Identifiable Information (Non-PII): Information that does not directly identify or cannot reasonably be used to figure out the identity of a user.  Non-PII is linked or reasonably linkable to a particular computer or device.  Non-PII does not include aggregate or anonymous data. 
> 
> Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”): Information which that directly identifies or reasonably can be used to figure out the identity of a user, such as your name, address, phone number, and email address.  Personal information does not include information that has been made anonymous so that it does not identify a specific user.
> 
> Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”): SSL technology allows for the encryption of information as it leaves your computer, making it nearly impossible for anyone other than the intended recipient to decrypt it.

## II. How Your Information is Collected and Used BY CTIA.ORG®

CTIA collects information from you in two primary ways: (1) information that you provide, and (2) information we collect automatically.

**Information You Provide**  
CTIA collects information that you voluntarily provide to CTIA.ORG® when you register for, purchase, or use our services or products.  CTIA will not use the information provided for any purpose other than the purpose for which it was submitted.  For example, some of the ways you may provide information to CTIA.ORG® include:

  * When you voluntarily register to receive the WOW newsletter, you will be asked to provide name, email address, company, and title.  CTIA will not use the registration information for any purpose other than delivering the newsletter.  Furthermore, if you later decide that you do not wish to receive the newsletter, you can opt out by clicking the “unsubscribe” link included in each email distribution of the newsletter. 
  * When you choose to purchase a product or service through the E-Store, you will be asked to provide contact information (such as name and mailing or shipping address) and payment information (such as credit card number and expiration date).  This information will only be used to record and fill your order or to communicate with you regarding your order.
  * If your company chooses to pursue membership with our Association, you will be asked to fill out an online application. The online application will request company contact information in order to help CTIA process your membership request. Depending on the type of membership your company pursues, you may have the option to provide payment information as well (such as company credit card number and expiration date). This information will only be used to communicate with your company regarding your application and to process your membership. 
  * If you apply to a job opening at CTIA, you may be asked to submit a job application or a resume. CTIA may use information collected during the application process to communicate with you and evaluate your qualifications for potential employment.

CTIA also contracts with third party service providers that perform certain functions and services for CTIA.ORG®.  There may be some portions of CTIA.ORG® that ask you to provide information, which is then collected by a third party performing services on our behalf. 

**Information We Collect Automatically**  
As you navigate through and interact with CTIA.ORG®, we may use cookies and other technologies that automatically collect specific information about your device, browsing actions, and usage of our website.  Allowing us to view this information helps us to improve CTIA.ORG® and to deliver a more personalized service, speed up your searches, and store information about your preferences.

Cookies and other Tracking Technologies   
CTIA may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you interact with our website.  CTIA uses cookies to help you navigate CTIA.ORG® as easily as possible.  For example, cookies allow the CTIA.ORG® Website to remember your registration and display settings when you return so you do not have to enter the same information each time you visit.

Please note that most web browsers allow you to turn off cookies on your computer by adjusting the web browser’s settings.  If you choose to turn off cookies, you may still use CTIA.ORG®, but your ability to use some areas or functions of the site may be limited.  You can learn more about managing your cookies in Section VI on Consumer Control and Choices.

Third-Party Advertising Partners  
CTIA uses our third-party ad partner to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet. Currently, we use third party-placed tracking pixels and cookies from the following advertising partner: Worldata. In the future we may partner with other companies to provide interest-based advertising, both on and off CTIA.org. If this occurs, we will provide you with an opportunity to opt out when these advertisements are served. 

These advertising service providers may collect non-personal information about your visits to CTIA.org, such as the content viewed, the date and time that such content is viewed, or the purchase being made. Such non-identifiable information does not include your name, address, email address or other personal information. The information is collected through the use of cookies and pixel tags (also known as action tags), which is industry-standard technology used by most major websites. 

In addition to the information about your visits to our website, our service providers may also use the information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements for services available from CTIA.org. 

Web Browser Activity Information   
In order to learn more about the use of CTIA.ORG®,  CTIA automatically collects information about your device and your visit, such as the type of browser you use, the times you accessed the site, the pages you viewed, your IP address, and the Web page you visited before visiting CTIA.ORG®.  This data allows us to become more familiar with people who visit our site, how frequently they visit, and what parts of the site they visit most often.  It is important to note that the information that we automatically collect is statistical data, and does not identify you as an individual.

## III. How Your Information is Shared

CTIA will only share information in accordance with the terms set forth directly below:

Consent   
CTIA will only disclose information about you to third parties with your consent which could be online or offline.  We may obtain your consent in writing, online via “click-through” agreements, orally, or through other manifestations of assent. 

Service Providers   
CTIA may share information that you provide with other companies that complete transactions and perform services on our behalf (for example, credit/debit card processing, billing, and shipping). These service providers are permitted to use the information only for the purpose provided to them and in a manner consistent with this Policy.  We require our service providers to comply with standard industry protocol around security, retention, use and destruction of any personal information that we provide to them or that they collect on our behalf.

Legal Purposes   
CTIA may access, monitor, use, or disclose your information or communications with us in order to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena, or court order); to respond to emergencies; to enforce an agreement with you, or to protect our rights or property, or the rights or property of our agents, vendors and service providers, members, and customers.

## IV. Children

CTIA.ORG® will not intentionally collect any personal information (such as a child’s name or e-mail address) from children under the age of 13. If you think that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, please contact us using the information listed below in the section titled “Contacting Us.”

## V. Data Protection 

**Security**  
The security of your information is important to CTIA.  Therefore, CTIA follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the security and confidentiality of your information while it is under our control.  We maintain physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect against the loss, misuse, and unauthorized access of your information.  For instance, we limit access to your information to only those authorized employees who need to know that information to provide benefits or services to you.  In addition, when you provide sensitive information (such as credit card numbers) through our E-Store, we take enhanced security precautions by using encryption technologies like Secure Socket Layer (SSL).  Please be aware that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting credit card information.  If you have any questions about the security of CTIA.ORG®, you can send an email to [ctiamedrel@ctia.org](mailto:ctiamedrel@ctia.org). 

**Data Retention**  
CTIA retains information only as long as necessary for business or tax purposes or as applicable laws, regulations, or government orders require.  When we dispose of information, we comply with standard industry procedures to ensure that it is properly deleted or rendered unreadable.

## VI. Other Websites and Links

This Privacy Policy only addresses CTIA’s collection, use, and disclosure of your information through the CTIA.ORG® website.  CTIA.ORG® contains links to other websites with privacy practices that may differ from those of CTIA.ORG®.  If you choose to click on a link and visit another website, please be aware that your information is governed by that website’s privacy policy.  CTIA encourages you to carefully read and review the policies and practices of the sites you visit. 

Please note that CTIA has other websites besides CTIA.ORG® related to CTIA’s tradeshows and events, as well as specific industry advocacy efforts and campaigns that may be accessed by clicking on links located on CTIA.ORG®.  These CTIA publications may be managed by different privacy policies. Therefore, CTIA recommends that you review the respective privacy policy for the website in which you are visiting prior to using the website. 

## VII. Consumer Control and Choices

Modifications and Updates  
CTIA.ORG® allows its users the option to modify and update information previously provided. This may be done through the following methods:

  1. E-mail the information to [webmaster@ctia.org](mailto:webmaster@ctia.org); or 
  2. Visit the Registration Section of the CTIA.ORG® Website and follow the appropriate instructions.

 CTIA will use reasonable efforts to ensure that your information is modified or updated in our records.

Correspondence  
You may choose to receive email from CTIA.  Please note that each email contains an accessible link offering you with the option to unsubscribe. 

Managing Cookies  
You can manage cookies by using tools available on most internet browsers.  Instructions for popular browsers are located at the following links:

## VIII. Notices and Changes to Our Privacy Statement

As our organization changes from time to time, this Privacy Policy may change as well.  We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version on our website.  The revised version will be effective at the time we post it.  Your continued use of this site following the posting of any change shall constitute your acceptance thereof.  The provisions contained herein supersede all previous notices or privacy policies and the terms and conditions that govern the use of CTIA.ORG®.

## IX. Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with the CTIA.ORG® Website, you can contact us at [webmaster@ctia.org](mailto:webmaster@ctia.org).

Last updated: June 2015
